Bernd Gustav Brügmann Klein

Industrial Engineer and Master in Finance

El Arcángel 4600Ap. 306 Vitacura, Santiago Chile Mobile Phone:+56 979888256 bbrugmann@gmail.com

Summary

Industrial Engineer and Master in Finance with over 15 years experience (10 years leading teams) in financial, industrial, service, audit and consultant companies. Strong financial management skills, organization skills with the ability to prioritize and work effectively on multiple tasks in a fast-paced environment.

Driven for results, keeping a healthy relationship through the company, have strong interpersonal skill, including the ability to interact and influence at all levels. Have leadership and motivation skills, encouraging my direct report seeking its professional development.

Professional Experience and Achievements

Volvo Financial Services Chile S.A. (Jan 2019 – Jan 2023)

CFO

- Responsible for the financial management of VFS Chile to ensure the company meets profitability and ROE requirements.
- Responsible for all management reporting measuring the performance of the business including profitability, risk management, pricing, volume, treasury and funding, expense control and reserve analysis
- Responsible for the production of strategic plans, including, annual and rolling forecasts, expenses, volume forecasts, and funding plans.
- Responsible for managing general accounting personnel and functions and maintaining appropriate controls ensuring compliance with Volvo Group and tax regulatory requirements.
- Responsible for the managing relationship with tax authorities and development of effective and optimized tax strategies. Ensure compliance with IFRS, tax, and government regulatory requirements.
- Responsible for the funding and execution of Capital Markets strategies, including relationship with banks.
- Responsible for the tender process and execution of RED (Former Transantiago).
- Contact point with Transportation Ministry, for the tender process and milestones accomplishments.

Monsanto Chile S.A. (Sep 2017 – Dec 2018)

FP&A Manager for Region South America

- In charge of South American FP&A team, ensuring accuracy, forecast and reporting Process improvement.
- Responsible for monthly financial statements reporting to headquarters (Saint Louis) with a Gap analysis and business rationale.
- Active participation in each monthly Commercial Forecast process, supporting Sales Team to define their best estimations and report the updated forecast to headquarters with the explanations of the most significant variations.

Intesis S.A. - Santiago (Mar 2016 - May 2017)

CFO

- Responsible for the quarterly financial statements under IFRS reporting.
- Responsible for all funding related activities keeping relationship with Banks and Financial companies of business partners entities (HP Financial, IBM Global Financing, others)
- Support stakeholders in strategic decision-making with the accurate financial information, including forecasts and business deal pricings.
- Responsible for the financial operational processes, accounting, tax, treasury, collections and invoicing.

GM Financial - Santiago (2011 - Feb 2016)

FP&A Manager

- Responsible for monthly reporting of financial statements to headquarters with a gap analysis to prior months the Business Plan.
- Responsible for the profitability model for Consumer and Commercial Plans, identifying risks and opportunities for the business.
- Monthly presentation of results and KPI's to the Board, advising regards the business trends.
- Development of Business Plan (4 years horizon), including sales estimations, operating expenses, incomes and assets definitions.
- Responsible for the profitability model and elaboration of market benchmarks.
- Responsible for the regulatory reports to the SBIF as well as internal and external audits.
- I led the process of the business core system change from the finance, accounting, products set and reporting point of view, complementing them with other business teams.
- Development and implementation of project excellence BPMS (Business Process Management System) for Finance area.

Nexans Chile - Santiago.

Financial Analyst and Hedge Operator (2009-2011)

- Responsible for the definition and implementation of the hedge strategy to mitigate foreign exchange rate and copper price fluctuations.
- Responsible for the hedge operation, forward rates negotiation with Bank Operators and monthly valuation under IFRS.
- Responsible for the valuation of financial derivatives (mark to market) and accounting under IFRS.
- Preparation of financial reports to headquarters, such as copper price, foreign exchange rate exposure, balance sheets and cash flows.

Deloitte - Santiago.

Consultant (2006 a 2009)

- Internal controls of business cycles and SOX controls attestation for the main financial companies and banks of the country.
- Responsible for the valuation (mark to market) of financial derivatives forwards, swaps, futures, options, fixed income instruments supporting financial audit team.
- Money desk audits, front, middle and back office control attestation for the main banks.

Education

- CFA (Chartered Financial Analyst) Level 1 Candidate(2016-2017)
- Master in Finance- Universidad Adolfo Ibáñez (2008-2009)
- Evaluation of real estate projects Seminar Universidad Adolfo Ibáñez(2008)
- IndustryEngineer- Universidad de la Frontera(1999 2005)
- High School exchange program-Gymnasium Oberursel(Germany) (Jan-Mar 1997)
- Elementary and high School Goethe Schule (Asunción, Paraguay)
- Elementary School Goethe Schule (Buenos Aires, Argentina)
- Elementary School- St. Bernhardt Grundschule (Esslingen, Alemania)

Languages

- SpanishNative
- German Native
- English, Fluent.

Software

- Microsoft Office Suite (advanced)
- ERP system (SAP R3, SAP Business One, Oracle Financial).
- Oracle Hyperion Essbase
- Bloomberg, Metastock, Crystal Ball.

Tranings and Workshops

- Situational leadership, leadership styles, feed-back practice.
- Speed of Trust
- Anti money laundering and frauds.
- Technical and Investment Analysis.
- Importsfrom China
- IFRS accountingstandards.
- Money deskauditcontrols.
- Processmaps.

Personal Information

Nationality: German (Permanent residence in Chile)

Civil status Married
TaxID: 14.628.742-5

Interests: Soccer, reading, tenis, padel, biking, trekking.

• Mobile Phone: +56-9-79888256